Hao Phung

Research interests

My primary research interests lie in the field of Computer Vision, with a specific focus on deep generative models. Currently, I am actively engaged in improving the efficiency and controllability of diffusion models, particularly in their application to conditional image generation.

EDUCATION

Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City - University of Science

Viet Nam

Bachelor of Computer Science; GPA: 8.40/10 (in-major GPA: 9.05/10); Rank: 14/320

Aug 2016 - Nov 2020

o Coursework: Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Data structures & Algorithms.

Honors thesis: Human action monitoring based on Visual question answering Advisor: Assoc. Prof. Ngoc Quoc Ly; Grade: 10/10

Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

• Utilized human-prior knowledge formed as Task Ontology to instruct the system what visual tasks should be performed to produce a suitable answer for an input query under Surveillance context.

PUBLICATIONS

(*) denotes equal contribution

- Quan Dao*, Hao Phung*, Binh Nguyen, Anh Tran, Flow Matching in Latent Space, arXiv preprint, 2023. [paper, code, page]
- Thanh Van Le*, Hao Phung*, Thuan Hoang Nguyen*, Quan Dao*, Ngoc Tran, Anh Tran, Anti-DreamBooth: Protecting users from personalized text-to-image synthesis, in *International Conference on Computer* Vision (ICCV), 2023. [paper, code, page]
- Hao Phung*, Quan Dao*, and Anh Tran, Wavelet Diffusion Models are fast and scalable Image Generators, in Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023. [paper, code]
- H. Vo*, T.H. Phung*, and N. Ly, VQASTO: Visual Question Answering System for Action Surveillance based on Task Ontology, in NAFOSTED Conference on Information and Computer Science (NICS), 2020. [paper]

EXPERIENCE

VinAI Research

Hanoi, Vietnam

Aug 2021 - now

- AI Research Resident Advised by Dr. Anh Tran
 - o Project: Flow Matching in Latent Space
 - * Introduce a latent flow matching framework that targets high-resolution image synthesis and various types of conditional image synthesis.
 - o Project: Anti-DreamBooth: Protecting Users from Personalized Text-to-Image Synthesis
 - * Introduce perturbation learning algorithms for enhanced user protection against malicious risks in personalized text-to-image synthesis.
 - Project: Wavelet Diffusion Models are fast and scalable Image Generators
 - * Propose a wavelet-based diffusion scheme that accelerates image generation by leveraging low- and high-frequency components of wavelet subbands at the image and feature levels.
 - * Achieve near real-time performance, effectively narrowing the speed gap with GAN counterparts.

Applied Rotation Program - Led by Mr. Tin Trung Duong

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

• Present a pipeline for Object Search using Open Vocabulary Object Detection that enables the retrieval of similar outputs based on a query object.

- Investigated SOTA semi-supervised learning for Image Classification and Monocular 3D Object Detection.
- Validated and benchmarked AI models for Autopilot projects (e.g. Camera Degradation, Lane detection).

Skeleton-Based Abnormal Behavior Recognition

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Research Collaborator - Led by Assoc. Prof. Ngoc Quoc Ly (cooperated with SNA Global)

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

- Developed a real-time anomaly action recognition system by enhancing time efficiency for pose tracking and transforming skeleton sequence to image as new spatio-temporal feature for action recognition.
- Improved accuracy of action recognition model by leveraging EfficientNet models and built up a minimal website using Flask framework for demonstration.

KMS Technology

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

AI Engineer Intern - Advised by Mr. Hoa Trong Vu

Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

- Created new dataset (nearly 3000 images) by collecting and refining images manually for Image matching problem. Also, utilized Image Hashing algorithm for filtering out similar samples.
- \circ Increased accuracy by 2.5% (at 96.5%) through fine-tuning state-of-the-art ImageNet models and adding new augmentation methods on the new dataset.

OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

• Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR)

Apr 2019 - Jun 2019

- Redesigned a handcraft algorithm for ALPR by adding FloodFill algorithm to extract plate more precisely and post-processing character image in plate to increase the accuracy of plate number recognition.
- Extended ALPR for motorbike plate recognition by utilizing Haar-Cascade Classifier to detect the plate.
- Tech stack: Python, OpenCV, Haar Cascade Classifier, SVM, Tesseract-OCR, Git.

• Face Recognition

May 2019 - Jun 2019

- Built a model for face recognition through utilizing cutting-edge face detection methods (e.g. SSD, Multitask-CNN) and optimizing the SVM model for identity recognition on our dataset.
- Adopted FaceNet for feature extraction as input to SVM model.
- o Tech stack: Python, OpenCV, SSD, FaceNet, SVM, Facial landmarks, Git.

Professional activities

• Reviewer: TPAMI (2023)

Honours and Awards

• Outstanding thesis award

2020

• Top 5 IT students in academic year

2018 - 2019

Programming Skills

• Languages: Python, C/C++, HTML/CSS, SQL.

• Technologies: PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Git, LATEX, Docker, Linux.

LANGUAGES

• Vietnamese: Native

• English: IELTS Academic 7.0

• Cantonese: Beginner

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

AI Day 2022

Panel speaker

Hanoi, Vietnam

Aug 2022